
Saturn-South Node: increase in responsibilities to do with fam- 
ily or ^tribe;" fated, karmic bonds are changed in such a way 
that the person has to carry a greater load. 

--

Pluto-Vertex/Antivertex: Encountering an individual or place 
with whom you feel a deep karmic bond. 


--
tionship to your family, a death in the family, or an ending in 
some way. In addition it can also be a time of increased aware- 
ness of the effect of family inherited karma or patterns. 


