whenever an intention of yours comes into conflict with your conscious belief about
what is right, moral or correct. In order to work out your particular intentions (or if
you prefer, karma), you must have a certain kind of experience, but you cannot
simply go out and have that experience because your belief system or ethical system
forbids it. In that case you experience the event as something that happens to you,
--
One common manifestation of this transit is becoming involved in a relationship
that makes very heavy demands on you. Although you would rather not be involved
in it, you find it difficult to break out of. These relationships can be called "karmic"
in that they balance out your past actions and are the direct or indirect consequence
of those actions. All you can do in this case is to persist and do whatever you have to
do. At a certain point you will realize that the karma has been completed; that is, the


--
this can happen through an increased concern with metaphysical and spiritual truth.
You may begin the serious study of a metaphysical discipline during this transit. You
may become very interested in such ideas as karma and reincarnation, and you will


--
Biquintile, meaning of, 29                           significance of, 265-266
Bradley, Donald, 31
Butterfield, Herbert, 41                           Karma, 5

Carter, Charles, xi                                Locality chart, 40-41
