any action that brings slow but permanent rewards. It is
a favorable time to progress in domestic and vocational
affairs. Uranus brings a spark to the life, where meeting
new and interesting people create scope for unexpected
opportunities and an up-tempo personal life. Pluto lends
energy to expend in relation to the personal and
domestic life. It's an excellent time to start new projects
or ventures that will improve personal and domestic
conditions. Masculine figures or powerful people are
often helpful.
--
--
fleeting. Mars in aspect to the Moon is very similar to
Pluto, described above. Its adverse aspects can be
especially annoying, when caution is needed to avoid
conflicts. Jupiter in fortunate aspect to the Moon is a
time of optimism, expansion, and travel, and for
domestic, business, and financial success. Relations
with women are good
--
become more progressive and to overcome a fear of
change. Thus the early lessons signified by the stressful
aspects of Uranus may be a necessary prerequisite for
--
Kidnapping
--
meaning as the Aries Point signatures. Converse
progressed Moon is also square converse progressed
Venus, an emotional time, and one of disagreements in
family relations.

   In checking the rest of the transits, Pluto squares
natal Sun while Mars is square progressed Sun.
Combined with other indicators these suggest power
struggles, conflicts, and forceful elements. Transiting
--
also reflecting the name change and suggesting that a
trip would follow shortly (the honeymoon). Transiting
--
breakups. Transiting Neptune, planet of mystery, was in
a wide square to natal Venus. It signified
disillusionment through a romantic relationship, when
the partner may be disloyal.

   She also had an opposition from transiting Pluto to
her progressed Venus in the natal 5th house. This aspect
reflects the increasing difficulty she'd noticed recently
in trying to understand Brad and their relationship. He
had not been supportive when her mom died and had
actually started to back off then, just when she needed
--

                          145
--
its detriment. Venus is semi-square the Sun, and she has
--
the Moon of one is in the same sign as Uranus in the
other. This, as well as Venus/Uranus combinations can
lead to romance, and with Venus, it may mean a sudden
attraction or even love at first sight.

   Pluto is similar to Mars when joined with other
planets. Pluto conjunct the Sun can indicate sexual
attraction but a clash of wills. It is the same with Pluto
and Mars joined. With Moon in hard aspect to Pluto,
there can be attempts to remake the Moon individual by
the Pluto person. Pluto in aspect to Venus signals strong
romantic sexual attractions, and this acts in a similar
fashion as Mars to Venus aspects.

   When there is a planet of one person connecting to
the Ascendant of the other person, this will cause
--
--
promises.)

   Venus rules the women in Lee's life whom he might
wish to form a cooperative effort with. It is involved in
a trine to Neptune and a sextile to Pluto. Such a
combination indicates karmic or fated attractions, the
possibility of finding the true soul mate, and idealistic
expectations in matters of love. The only downfall is the
tendency for Lee to over-idealize a partner. This can
make it difficult for the partner, who may feel she
--
               EST; 85W40, 40N33

   His progressed Moon is sextile his progressed
Midheaven and natal Venus while it conjoins
progressed Mars, showing event potential involving a
new relationship. Transiting Pluto conjuncts natal
Neptune. From there, Pluto forms a sextile to
progressed Moon and progressed Mars while in trine to
natal Venus, stimulating the most romantic patterns.
While transiting Pluto is trine the radical Venus, it is
square progressed Venus. Since these contacts repeat a
natal theme, they become important in distinguishing
that this relationship will fulfill the natal promise of a
fated quality. Although these two are in good aspect in
the natal chart, the current square may be problematic.
There's a strong desire and urgency to find love but
with Pluto square his progressed Venus, Lee may be too
hasty in choosing a partner.
--
second aspect suggests misleading impulses and
accentuates the themes of unrealistic expectations,
increasing the chances for disillusionment. Transiting
Pluto ties into this theme by square and conjunction and
indicates that manipulation, jealousy, or power
struggles for control within the relationship could

be a problem and might bring explosive situations.

--
Moon. With important rulers of the marriage house in
--

   The ruler of the 5th house is Venus in Sagittarius.
This sign position for Venus suggests someone who
--
   Progressed Mars is conjunct natal Venus, indicating
that the time is ripe for a romantic relationship to
develop. Progressed Venus is sextile natal Uranus. As
seen earlier, sudden magnetic attractions are typical
under such an influence, although not necessarily
permanent. Transiting Pluto is in conjunction to natal
Venus and progressed Mars, showing the desire for a
romantic attachment and that there may be some
profound experiences that involve affairs of the heart
--
in the outer wheel.

   Obvious right from the beginning is that Trish's Pluto
is conjunct Lee's Ascendant. This can be quite a
profound influence. She will fulfill the natal potential in
his chart as it calls for karmic ties, and she can bring
about deep changes within him. Neither of them will be
the same as a result of this relationship.
--
attraction, but also tensions and quarrels.

   Her Mars is square his Venus, fostering sexual
attraction, but also a tendency to argue.

   Her Pluto on his Ascendant suggests an intense
relationship with potential control issues.

   Her Moon is closely square his Moon, causing
difficulties in understanding one another's feelings.

--
--
                         update

The strong Plutonian factors seen in the charts came
through in full force. Several breakups and makeups
occurred between Lee and Trish. Both went through
deep changes as a result of the relationship and attempts
to make it work. They felt compelled to be together, yet
had clashes of wills over the control and direction of the
relationship. Their first big split postponed their
engagement indefinitely. Lee was quite crushed by this
first breakup, but he immediately began seeing someone
else. He and Trish then got back together, but had
another serious and final breakup. At that time Lee's
progressed Moon came into orb with Trish's natal Pluto.
--
oppose natal Venus and square natal Mars, again
stimulating a discordant natal aspect. This particular
link between Mars and Pluto sometimes shows danger
or an actual attack to the individual. The opposition of
Pluto to Venus is also one of forceful situations in
relationships. The long duration of Pluto's afflicting
aspects reflect the long spell that Dixie was abused.
Neptune also remained in conjunction to her natal or
progressed Ascendant for years. These aspects are
behind her feeling of being preyed upon for several
years.
--
the sad days ahead, is seen with the transiting South
Node moving over Donna's progressed Moon. This is
usually a melancholy time. Often there are personal,
--

Libra: partnerships, other people,         relationships,
  cooperation (ruled by Venus)

Scorpio: time for change, transforming, intense, energy,
  willpower (ruled by Pluto)

--
accidents. Solar Return Mars and natal Uranus are the
most angular planets in the return chart. His Solar
Return Moon is in a close square to return Pluto. The
Moon rules the Solar Return 4th house, an indication of
intense or violent emotional outbursts in family
relations. Of course it was a domestic dispute he was
responding to in the line of duty when the perpetrator

--
fateful 911 call and his subsequent injury, shows that
return Mars occupies the Lunar Return 1st house. This
--
surface in some way, from miners to psychologists, and
those whose work deals with death or refuge. It rules
underworld characters, uniformed workers, and
scientists. Pluto's function is to isolate, intensify, purge,
destroy, undermine, transmute, reinforce, or add a new
dimension. Pluto is reputed to deal with karma,
institutions, and police activity. Discovered at a time
when organized crime and kidnappings were making
headlines, Pluto stamped its significance with these
issues upon its entry to our awareness.

--
sources and earnings of the opposite house. It rules
regenerative processes, sex, and death. You may take
out a loan or have concerns about debts when an eclipse
falls here. The key phrase is "I desire," and this house
corresponds to Pluto. Permanent changes follow.
Intense relationships may develop.

   The 9th house governs higher learning and the
abstract mind, long-range vision, philosophy,
professors, religion, publishing, propaganda, and long
--
--
and there is increased power and inner strength to make
changes that were previously put off. It is a constructive
period with the power to greatly improve
circumstances. A South Node transit to Pluto brings
new conditions. There may be intense and complicated
relationships, often with power struggles or
confrontations. Some profound event may act as a
catalyst to new experience and a change of
consciousness. There may be closure of some
significant issue.

--
                          600
were also other disturbing indicators in each of these
--

   If the Solar Return Vertex is conjoined with a natal
planet, it suggests destined experiences of personal
significance. If conjoined with the Moon, for example,
there may be destined events impacting the family. If
Pluto is joined with the Vertex in the Solar Return,
there may be fateful experiences connecting to debts,
mortgages, or tax concerns. If the Vertex falls on
Neptune there may be the need for hospitalization or
some intrigue might touch the life. Falling on Mercury,
a job change may be destined.
--

Malefic: Planets that are associated with trouble are
 termed malefic. Mars and Saturn frequently
 correspond with stressful or harmful conditions,
