Point, proves it deserving of special notice for
predicting events. The zero degree of any cardinal sign
is representative of some entanglement with the world
at large. The Pleiades, a fixed star group in the last
degree of Taurus, is sometimes prominent at the time of
misfortune. These special points along with the Vertex,
which is a point of fate and destiny, and a condition
called Saturn Chasing the Moon, are presented and
commented on in delineation throughout this work.
These keys to prediction are also given special attention
in Part Three.
--
ventures and she is highly motivated to initiate them.
Transiting Sun in sextile to the progressed Midheaven
shows her good choice in timing to further her career.
Honor and achievement are indicated. Even the
transiting Moon trines her progressed Midheaven on
one side and her natal Part of Fortune/Vertex on the
other side as she departs from Boston to relocate in
New York. She is personally protected, but there is

                           65
potential to have an unusual or unexpected brush with
--
and Mars play such an important part in the timing of
events, the Moon is nearly always found to be transiting
a sensitive planet or point at the time of important
events. Many times it will be angular, or another angle
will be contacted, such as the nodal axis, or the
Vertex/Anti-vertex.

   Using the progressed Moon, and the forming aspects
it will make, helps to pinpoint the timing of events
when other long-term aspects are in force. Difficult
themes shown in the major progressions and transits
--
very profound and positive aspect, but if such things as
manipulation, jealousy, and control become an issue,
then a breakup can be quite a destructive one, and one
or both partners are likely to be devastated.

  Lee's Venus is conjunct her Vertex at 40 Leo, an
aspect somewhat similar to having his Venus conjunct
her Descendant. They both may feel it is a fated love.

   Her Midheaven is conjunct his Ascendant, an angular
connection that is karmic and often appears in the charts
--
the zero degree of a cardinal sign. Such a planet holds
an elevated status and significance. The Pleiades, a
group of stars in the last degree of Taurus, is associated
with the weeping sisters and is significant of potentially
unfortunate situations if a planet occupies its degree.
The Vertex, a point of fate, is informative if conjunct a
planet. Chapter 16 expands on each of these special
points.

       Usin3 the Solar k Lunar Returns To8ether

--
The following special points can be used in conjunction
with other prediction techniques. These points offer
specialized information when, on occasion, they
become highlighted or prominent in the chart. The
special points are the Pleiades, the Aries Point, Saturn
Chasing the Moon, and the Vertex. The symbolism of
each of these special points is discussed in this chapter.

                      The Pleiacles

A fixed star cluster known as the Pleiades is located in
--

                          597
chart must also be considered. Nothing can come to
pass that is not suggested in the natal chart.

                      The Vertex

The Vertex, which is the west end of the true east-west
axis through the birthplace, is associated with
experiences and encounters with others over which one
has little or no control. Astrology programs calculate
the Vertex for you.

  The significance of the Vertex is somewhat
comparable to the Descendant. This is where we attract
others to fill in missing parts of ourselves, or to play
those parts of ourselves that we disown.

   The degree opposite the Vertex is called the Anti-
vertex. It is like an auxiliary Ascendant, where we
personally identify. Edward Johndro pioneered research
to these points, noting the quality of destiny associated
with each. Similar to the Ascendant, Johndro called the
Anti-vertex the Electric Ascendant, and observed that
while the Ascendant shows free choice and volitional
life, the Electric Ascendant showed no choice and
involuntary actions.

  Later, Charles Jayne convinced Johndro that the
Vertex showed the greater emphasis as a point of fate.
Not only encounters with others, but also experiential
encounters are noted with the Vertex. It represents
appointments with destiny. Besides the lunar nodes, the

                          598
Vertex is a most "fateful" indicator.

   The Vertex appears to be a point of fated meetings
and karmic interactions. It is often active in ties
between individuals who seem to have a relationship of
a fateful quality, or who feel they may have known one
another in a previous incarnation. To illustrate, a
middle-aged couple met and immediately felt that they
--
those who knew them by the speed in which it
progressed. Those around them commented on how
they acted like an old married couple right from the
start, and that it would seem strange if they were not
together. In this case, his Sun is closely conjunct her
Vertex. The woman says that it felt as if their souls had
always been holding hands, and that they had just
finally met in the flesh. The man says he felt as if he
already knew everything about her from the moment
they met. They were engaged within two weeks, and
when they married five months later, the transiting
North Node was exactly conjunct her Vertex and his
Sun. This further reflects a re

lationship where the couple is destined to experience
major life events together due to the common ground of
his Sun and her Vertex.

   The relationship between Lee and Trish (see chapter
3) shows that his natal Venus was conjunct her Vertex,

                           599
a powerful connection to draw them together. In this
case, even though other planetary configurations
indicated problems, they still wanted to be together.
This may be a revealing factor in relationships between
couples who have otherwise incompatible backgrounds,
beliefs, ages, and so on.

   While the Vertex seems to be very significant in
terms of relationships, it also appears to be a point of
destiny or karma for the individual in more personal
terms as well.

   In several instances the Solar or Lunar Return chart
prior to death contains the Vertex of the individual on
an important point. It appears frequently that the Vertex
is rising in these returns.

   Grant Lewi, a famous and inspiring astrologer and
author, had his natal Vertex rising in both his Solar and
Lunar Return prior to his death. Evangeline Adams had
her natal Vertex appearing on the Ascendant of her
converse Lunar Return prior to her death. The South
Node was conjunct her natal Vertex in her Solar Return
prior to her death. The natal Vertex was rising in
President Kennedy's Solar Return chart prior to his
assassination, and several planets were transiting his
Vertex in the Lunar Return before the event. In Elvis
Presley's Solar Return prior to his death, Pluto
conjoined his natal Vertex. The nodes were transiting
his Vertex axis at the time of his death. Of course there

                          600
were also other disturbing indicators in each of these
cases, and the significance of the Vertex must be
considered alongside remaining features.

   If the Solar Return Vertex is conjoined with a natal
planet, it suggests destined experiences of personal
significance. If conjoined with the Moon, for example,
there may be destined events impacting the family. If
Pluto is joined with the Vertex in the Solar Return,
there may be fateful experiences connecting to debts,
mortgages, or tax concerns. If the Vertex falls on
Neptune there may be the need for hospitalization or
some intrigue might touch the life. Falling on Mercury,
a job change may be destined.

   Reverse aspects also work. A Solar Return planet
falling on the natal Vertex is meaningful. With Solar
Return Mars conjoined with natal Vertex, there may be
a conflict with someone. If the return node is conjoined
with the natal Vertex this

might signify very fateful events. Always check for
verification from other chart features to refine your
interpretation. For any one event, many aspects will
show it.

  This point is also revealing when the Solar or Lunar
Return Vertex is conjoined with another return planet.
In that case, note the symbolism of the planet that is
conjunct the Vertex, which may represent a destined


                          601
appointment of a specific nature. There may be a
destined partnership if the planet is Venus, an
--
individual if Uranus, or with an authority figure if the
planet is Saturn.

   Check for any combination. Then watch for the
transit of the Moon or any other planet over the pair,
which may bring important developments. The Vertex
is a fascinating point, worthy of attention.

1. Nicholas DeVore. Encyclopedia of Astrology (New
  York: Philosophical Library, 1947), p 95.

--
Trine: A one-hundred-and-twenty-degree angle between
  two points. The trine is a major aspect, representing
  harmony, ease, and sometimes fortune, but it is
  undemanding of action.

Vertex: A point in the western hemisphere created by
 the intersection of the prime vertical with the ecliptic.
 Appears in many cases to be associated with
 encounters of a fateful nature, either with people or
 circumstances. Researched originally by L. Edward
 Johndro. See chapter 16.
