Chart Comparison & Summary ... 70            166
Update ... 74                                173
Synastry & the Sun ... 75                    175
Four: MONEY & SUCCESS                        181
A Self-Made Millionaire ... 81               186
--
   The Moon and Saturn, ruling the 4th and 10th
houses, are brought by close conjunction to the
Ascendant. This indicates an unusually karmic
relationship with her parents, and her relationship with
them has a deep impact on her. This combination of the
--
wish to form a cooperative effort with. It is involved in
a trine to Neptune and a sextile to Pluto. Such a
combination indicates karmic or fated attractions, the
possibility of finding the true soul mate, and idealistic
expectations in matters of love. The only downfall is the
--
is conjunct Lee's Ascendant. This can be quite a
profound influence. She will fulfill the natal potential in
his chart as it calls for karmic ties, and she can bring
about deep changes within him. Neither of them will be
the same as a result of this relationship.
--

   Her Midheaven is conjunct his Ascendant, an angular
connection that is karmic and often appears in the charts
of married couples.

--
some rocky roads.

                   Synastry k the Sun

An excellent starting point in analyzing any relationship
--
planet.

  The nodes are considered karmic in nature. Traveling
backward through the

zodiac they reconnect one with things of the past. They
symbolize give and take, learning life lessons, playing
by the laws of the universe, reaping karmic rewards,
and paying karmic debts. The North Node is more
representative of opportunities and good tidings, while
the South Node represents trials and tribulations. They
show karmic occurrences and reflection on destiny
issues. The return node or the natal node on an angle
may indicate a significant and possibly karmic
occurrence during the period of the return. On a non-
angular house cusp effects are similar but less profound
--
may bring serious consequences. North Node in the 1st
house suggests events that may seem particularly
karmic in nature.

  There is a lot of activity in the 10th house, showing a
--
tremendous inner resources and enormous endurance,
strength, and staying power. Any aspect may bring
contact with those with whom there is a karmic bond.
One might meet with destiny, or enter a new plane of

--
friendships. Latent artistic or creative talents can be
developed. These may bring a romantic attraction of
karmic proportions. Strong feelings are stimulated in

                          516
--
scientists. Pluto's function is to isolate, intensify, purge,
destroy, undermine, transmute, reinforce, or add a new
dimension. Pluto is reputed to deal with karma,
institutions, and police activity. Discovered at a time
when organized crime and kidnappings were making
--

                           542
Moon and portends karmic experiences. We are
evolving at a faster rate in the matters of the house
where an eclipse falls.
--

   An eclipse calls individuals to their personal
destinies, so when significant changes or karmic
connections lie ahead, an eclipse will announce it ahead
of time.
--
                           548
this house corresponds naturally with Venus. There
might be karmic attractions or separations.

  The 8th house governs taxes, insurance, inheritance,
--

   Events related to the nodes often appear to be
somewhat fated or karmic in nature. Traveling
backward a little more than one degree per month, as
they contact personal planets, they may show a time to
--
there may be vulnerabilities or sacrifices attached

to the things ruled by the planet. Karmic debts and past
obligations are attributed to the South Node, while the
accruing of karmic rewards and favors are linked to the
North Node.

--
increase in the social life. There is the need for a
reassessment of the finances and/or affections.
Sometimes a karmic attachment begins. There may be a
financial increase. A South Node transit to Venus
usually brings a low point when it comes to affections,
--

   A major crossroad appears when the nodes realign
with their natal position. This indicates karmic
transitions as an old phase of growth and experience
comes to an end and one enters into new experiences
--

   The configuration is an interesting one, especially
when Saturn's reputation as a karmic planet is taken into
consideration. The possibility for one of these extended
aspects is totally dependent on the Moon's rate of speed
--
personal and professional affairs. Maybe these aspects
should be called Saturn Shining on the Moon. Does this
mean that these individuals have karmic rewards
coming for past good deeds? It is possible. This
progressed aspect was found in the chart of Dan in
--

   The Vertex appears to be a point of fated meetings
and karmic interactions. It is often active in ties
between individuals who seem to have a relationship of
a fateful quality, or who feel they may have known one
--
   While the Vertex seems to be very significant in
terms of relationships, it also appears to be a point of
destiny or karma for the individual in more personal
terms as well.

--
  Jupiter, and Saturn returns.

Lunar Nodes, Discover Your Soul's Karmic Mission.
 Woodbury, MN: Llewellyn Worldwide, 2008. Learn
 to interpret your nodes' positions and each of their
 aspects. Provides descriptions for nodal contacts in
 the natal, progressed, return charts, and from transits.
 Provides nodal connections in synastry and more. A
 comprehensive reference on the Lunar Nodes.

--
 horizon.

Karma: The rewards for past deeds, whether positive or
 negative. Karma is an objective, impersonal balancing
 mechanism existing in the universal spirit.

